# RHIANNE BRUCE

07393982375

rhiannebruce98@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/rhianne-bruce ·

I am an approachable individual with a positive attitude in everything I do. My current aim is to gain experience and get a permanent role within software development. My strong critical thinking skills help me evaluate the choices that I make, giving me pride in my work and allowing me to push myself in every task given.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **WEB DESIGNER:** GOOD LIFE DOG WALKING

### **JUNE 2021-CURRENT**

I am currently helping a local dog walking company update their website.

- Redesigning a WordPress based website.
- Using HTML to edit key elements.
- Researching plugins to help support the development of the website.
- Meeting with the client to present changes and receive feedback.

### **RESEARCHER: NOTTINGHAM TRENT UNIVERSITY**

# **JANUARY- MARCH 2020**

I worked within a team researching how to engage students to the NTU's sustainability team's app on tracking sustainability, called Green Rewards.

- Created and conducted surveys and focus groups.
- Planned different approaches to promoting the project on social media.
- Collating key findings into a presentable format that we then presented as a group.
- Collaboratively wrote a final report, detailing the findings of the project.

## **COUNTER/PHARMACY ASSISTANT: BLACKWELL PHARMACY**

### 2015 - 2018

After completing work experience with them, they offered me a part-time job during my A-Level studies.

- Trusted to handle drugs and personal information when completing prescriptions.
- Checked and organized items from delivery.
- Strong attention to detail due to undertaking accuracy checks on assembled prescriptions before final check by the pharmacist.

# **EDUCATION/QUALIFICATIONS**

# BA (HONS) POLITICS AND INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS: NOTTINGHAM TRENT

**UNIVERSITY** 

2018-2021

Awarded a high 2:1 overall in my studies.

- Wrote a 12,000-word dissertation focused on environmental political theory and how this is studied within literature and the wider context, strengthening my research and writing skills.
- Led and taken part in group work involving discussion, decision-making and organization, increasing my confidence in communication and coordination.
- Achieved a Nottingham Trent University Employability Digital Gold Award, choosing the digital marketing pathway.

# **INTRODUCTION TO WED DEVLOPMENT: CODE FIRST GIRLS**

#### **MAY 2020**

Completed a Code First Girls course on web development, submitting a final project for which I was awarded best on the course.

- Learnt basic HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Created wireframes to support planning of final website.
- Applied these skills to create a book review website from scratch.

### THE FUNDAMENTALS OF DIGITAL MARKETING: GOOGLE DIGITAL GARAGE

### **JANUARY 2020**

Completed the certification of fundamentals in digital marketing with modules such as:

- The basics of an SEO strategy for an online business.
- Understanding how search engines work to aid business presence.
- Using social media to further support a business's online presence.

**A-LEVELS:** ASHFIELD POST-16 CENTRE

2015-2018

History: B Geography: B English Literature: C

**GCSES:** FREDERICK GENT SCHOOL

**2010-2015** 11 A\*- C

# **SKILLS**

- Excellent analytical and critical skills
- Confident in communication with others
- Basic knowledge of HTML, CSS and WordPress
- Use of Microsoft Office
- Precise time management
- Working on large projects

# **ACTIVITIES**

I have an interest in coding:

- Strengthening my programming skills by learning new languages such as Python and C# with Codecademy.
- Experimenting with my programming knowledge in Visual Studio to get used to using an IDE. I took part in the Digital Marketing Academy ran by Nottingham Trent University and University of Nottingham:
  - Looked at the SEO of a company and pitched recommendations.
  - Created content in the form of a blog post.